{
    "id": "bd4f44087056426b9482cbe5a8dd89a7",
    "title": "Pronouns exercise for beginners",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Peter's mother went to the market. He went with ..................................",
            "description": "We need an object pronoun (him, her, them, us) after a preposition. Note that the pronouns you and it have the same subject and object forms. ",
            "answers": [
                "she",
                "her"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3c8cf4b70ea8443d9e645d3600202b4e"
        },
        {
            "question": "The children are playing in the park. ............................. are having a great time.",
            "description": "We need a plural pronoun to refer to a plural noun. He and she are singular.",
            "answers": [
                "He",
                "She",
                "They"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "ef2f03cd8806489bbf07d3caa2eab8fe"
        },
        {
            "question": "Tom is running to catch the ball. ........................ is wearing a blue shirt.",
            "description": "We need a subject pronoun here. He is the subject form. Him is the object form. His is the possessive form. ",
            "answers": [
                "He",
                "Him",
                "His"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "660846ef4cad42beb11b04bdeedd9e90"
        },
        {
            "question": "Reddy Fox saw a monster. The monster frightened .......................",
            "description": "A pronoun used as the object should be in its object form. He is the subject form and him is the object form.",
            "answers": [
                "he",
                "him"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "53312e3c679b4ae78338a3a720785bbb"
        },
        {
            "question": "Don't eat this mango. ............................ is rotten.",
            "description": "We use 'it' to refer to things and animals.",
            "answers": [
                "It",
                "Its"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "6cf8c9e1e74f4fc980cc3d50e300c198"
        },
        {
            "question": "The students are making a lot of noise. Please ask ........................... to keep quiet.",
            "description": "Them is the object form of they.",
            "answers": [
                "they",
                "them",
                "their"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "7c9ecfb120ed479dac305c110bd92686"
        },
        {
            "question": "My brother likes storybooks. I bought this for ........................",
            "description": "The pronoun used as the object of a preposition should be in its object form. ",
            "answers": [
                "he",
                "him"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ec102ce64c3149df91527a11d7ed2f4a"
        },
        {
            "question": "Nancy is a good girl. Everybody likes .........................",
            "description": "Here the pronoun is the object of the verb 'likes', so it should be in its object form.",
            "answers": [
                "she",
                "her"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "fbc5a1b60e584644a30fdf730d28fd53"
        },
        {
            "question": ".............................. are going to the cinema. Do you want to come with ..........................?",
            "description": "Here the first pronoun is the subject and the second pronoun is the object. ",
            "answers": [
                "We, us",
                "We, we",
                "Us, we"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "2c1f39a31ffa4a01b9a60c8382354bdb"
        },
        {
            "question": "Don't eat this mango. I will get a good one for ....................",
            "description": "The pronoun 'you' has the same object and subject forms.",
            "answers": [
                "you",
                "your",
                "yours"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "de184dadd73d476096eaa2d91d486e44"
        },
        {
            "question": "That dog is ............................ This is .........................",
            "description": "His is the possessive form of he. Likewise, ours are the possessive form of we. ",
            "answers": [
                "him, us",
                "his, our",
                "his, ours"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "7fe34d8a03b546fcac4142c6c2acf8e8"
        },
        {
            "question": "My daughters like to watch Disney films. This CD is for ..........................",
            "description": "A pronoun used as the object of a preposition should be in its object form.",
            "answers": [
                "they",
                "them",
                "their"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f44673f65802458684d59a208da03035"
        }
    ]
}